Listen to part of a lecture in a college music class.
OK... That about does it for today.
We're going to spend the next few classes on a different kind of music.
We'll examine the development of jazz from its beginnings right on up to the latest in jazz music.
We'll look at jazz as the most successful music indigenous to the United States... born in New Orleans
and raised in Chicago and New York.
We'll begin with the African roots of the music
and how African rhythms blended with Western music to create an entirely new form.
Then we'll follow jazz into its heyday
the 1920's, which was known as the Jazz Age.
It was in this era that the blues were born.
The 1930's saw the evolution of "swing
jazz music played by the big bands like that of Tommy Dorsey.
If there's any generalization that can made about jazz,
it's that the music is always changing
evolving... from the Bebop of the '40's to the "cool jazz" of the '50's
and on into the experimental '60's.
The '70's saw jazz brought into the electronic age by artists like Herbie Hancock.
We'll end up listening to some examples of the newest transformation of jazz... Afro-pop
and the Latin beats that have brought new international flair to this music born in the United States.
Be sure to read chapters 13 and 14 of your text.
They'll get you started.
If there are any jazz devotees among you,
feel free to bring in your favorite tapes or CD's to share with the class.
Renee Rosnes' latest release would be great if anyone has it.